(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T09:36:24.487876",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あー、あー、あー。
Ah, ah, ah...
本日はさくらみこ 4周年バースデーライブ
Today, thank you so much for attending
バーチャルライブ2022にご来場いただき誠にありがとうございます！
the Sakura Miko 4th Anniversary Birthday Virtual Live 2022!
皆さん、にゃっはろー！
Everyone, Nyahallo!
はぎなれのさくらみこです。
It's the energetic Sakura Miko.
本日、18.4歳になりましたー！えへへへ。
Today, I turned 18.4 years old! Hehehe.
ええと、ちょっとあれだな、はぎなれっぽく読むの。
Um, trying to sound a bit energetic here.
開演に先立ちまして、ご来場のお客さまにお願いを申し上げます。
Before the show begins, we have a request for all attendees.
客席内での飲食は、ご遠慮なく平らげていただいても構いません。
Eating and drinking in the seating area is completely fine to enjoy freely.
自由に盛り上がってもらってオッケーです！
Feel free to get as hyped as you want!
むしろ、とーっくさん！はしゃぐさくらみこ生誕祭で、つぶやきながら盛り上がりまくってください！
In fact, please tweet lots and get super hyped at Sakura Miko's birthday celebration!
また、スクショで18.4歳になったこのエリートさくらみこちゃんをたくさん撮って投稿してくださいね！
Also, please take and post plenty of screenshots of elite Sakura Miko, now 18.4 years old!
それでは、まもなく開演でございます！みんな、みこのバースデーライブ楽しんでいってねー！
Well then, the show will begin shortly! Everyone, enjoy Miko's birthday live to the fullest!
いくよ
Let's go!
はちゃめちゃカラフルデイズ
Hachamecha colorful days!
攻略法を探している
Searching for a strategy,
リセットボタンなんて
As if there's a reset button,
あるわけないし 縛りプレイもいい所じゃない？！
And playing it safe is okay too, right?
そんなのわかきってる
I know that already!
それなら思い出して 夢を奏でる
Then remember it, playing our dreams,
あの星のことを
That star's story!
最初はダメダメでもいいからさ
It's okay to start out totally clumsy,
ほらリズムに合わせて 1 2 try and try!
Just match the rhythm: 1, 2, Try & Try!
予測不可能なんだ 本当のところは
The unpredictable truth of the matter is...
次のページのことだよ？ I don't know
It's about the next page! I don't know!
怖いことなんてないよ その続きにいっせーので飛び込んじゃおう
There's nothing to be afraid of, let's take the plunge into what's next!
準備はいい？
Are you ready?
だから Do my best! do my best!
So Do my best, do my best!
テンションは弾けてくらり
My tension is bursting through the roof!
Attention Please? Attention Please?
ドキドキのボリュームはMAXで行こうよ
Let's turn the pounding volume up to MAX!
泣いちゃって笑っちゃって エモーションもアタフタしてる
Crying and laughing, emotions are in a frenzy!
この今をめいっぱいさ 楽しんでいこうよ
Let's enjoy this moment to the fullest!
まだまだまなの止まれない そんな世界が大好きなんだよ
I just love a world that never stops growing!
声に出して do my best!
Say it out loud, do my best!
ちんぷんかんぷんカラフルデイズ
Chinpunkampun colorful days!
冒険の書はどこにもない
The book of adventure is nowhere to be found,
セーブポイントやり直しの毎日じゃ ワクワクの音色も奏でられない
And I can't even play the thrilling melodies.
そんなのつまんないでしょ？
Isn't that a little boring?
それなら耳を澄まして
Then open your ears wide,
大好きな音が聞こえてくるよ
And you'll hear your favorite sound!
明日は明日の風が吹くからさ ほらリズムに合わせて 1 2 try and try!
Tomorrow is another day, so match the rhythm: 1, 2, Try & Try!
やっぱ気になっちゃうな 本当のところは
I'm so curious, the truth is...
次のページのことだよ？ I want to know
It's about the next page! I want to know!
あふれるリズム繋いで
Tied together by an overflowing rhythm,
君だけの気持ちを今すぐ描いちゃおう
Let's capture your true feelings right now!
だから Do my best! do my best!
So Do my best, do my best!
クエスチョンがぐるぐるぐらり白昼夢中
Questions are spinning around in a daydream!
Attention Please? Attention Please?
キラキラのドリームはMAXで行こうよ
Let's turn the sparkling dreams up to MAX!
単純で難解なエモーションもアタフタしてる
Simple yet complex emotions are in a frenzy!
これからもめいっぱいさ 仲良くよろしくね
Let's get along great from now on too!
まだまだまあとどれくらい？ そんな明日を目指して
Aiming for a tomorrow that just keeps going,
いこうもう一歩！ do my best!
Let's go one step further! Do my best!
お星様にお願いごと
Making a wish upon a star,
早くそれになれますように
Hoping it comes true soon,
覚めないように魔法をかけて
Casting a spell so it never wakes up,
ワクワクが爆発しそうだよ
My excitement is about to explode!
今日はみこの誕生日パーティ！
Today is Miko's birthday party!
ゲストもいっぱい出るよ みんな盛り上がってね
Get lots of guests, everyone let's get hyped!
今気づいちゃったんだ 本当のところは
I just realized it, the truth is...
次のページのことだよ？ I can't wait
It's about the next page! I can't wait!
楽しみすぎるからさ その続きにいっせーので飛び込んじゃおう
Because it's way too fun, let's take the plunge into what's next!
だから Do my best! do my best!
So Do my best, do my best!
テンションは弾けてくらり
My tension is bursting through the roof!
Attention Please? Attention Please?
ドキドキのボリュームはMAXで行こうよ
Let's turn the pounding volume up to MAX!
泣いちゃって笑っちゃって エモーションもアタフタしてる
Crying and laughing, emotions are in a frenzy!
この今をめいっぱいさ 楽しんでいこうよ
Let's enjoy this moment to the fullest!
まだまだまなの止まれない そんな世界に大好き宣言
I just love a world that never stops growing!
声に出して do my best!
Say it out loud, do my best!
合言葉は どうまいべすと！
Our watchword is... Do my best!
いくぞ！ がんばれみこ！
Let's go! Hang in there, Miko!
サンキュー！ またねー！
Thank you, see you later!
また始まった
It started again...
また始まった 忘れんぼう
It started all over again, you forgetful one
手帳の隅っこだって カレンダーにだって マルして置いたのに
Even in the corner of my planner, circled on the calendar...
どうして怒ってるか おわかりですか？
Do you understand why I'm angry?
謝っても許さないんだからね
Even if you apologize, I won't forgive you!
もう知らない！
I'm done with you!
どこにでもあるような どこにもないような
Like something found anywhere, yet nowhere to be found...
シアワセ探しはまだ始まったばっか
The search for happiness has only just begun!
楽しみにしてたプリンだって 君に食べられる為に生まれたわけじゃなかったのにっさ
Even the pudding I was looking forward to wasn't born just to be eaten by you!
それ ちょっとだけ ちょうだい
Give me just a little bit of that.
ねえ一口だけ ちょうだいなんて
Saying "Hey, just one bite" like that—
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの？
Isn't that a bit too convenient for you?
飽きちゃったらいらない
If you get tired of it, you don't want it,
残しちゃったらごめんねって
And saying "Sorry" if you leave leftovers—
…君のせいかしら？
...Is it your fault?
一体全体私のことはどれくらい愛してるって言葉じゃなくて形で作ってよ
Just how much do you love me? Show me in actions, not just words!
今日が何の日か お忘れですか？
Have you forgotten what day today is?
でも誕生日だなんて言うのもちょっと癪ね
But saying it's my birthday also kind of irritates me!
もう知らない！
I'm done with you!
結婚するとかしないとか 子供は何人欲しいとか
Whether we'll get married or not, how many kids we want—
シアワセ家族計画を掲げる前に
Before setting up a happy family plan,
タバコやお酒は控えるとか 明日から真面目にやるっつーか
Cutting back on smoking and drinking, or starting to take things seriously tomorrow—
だらだら続けているじゃんじゃんじゃん
You just keep dragging it on and on, bang bang bang!
それ ちょっとだけ ちょうだい
Give me just a little bit of that.
ねえ一口だけ ちょうだいなんて
Saying "Hey, just one bite" like that—
あまりにも都合が良すぎじゃないの？
Isn't that a bit too convenient for you?
飽きちゃったらいらない
If you get tired of it, you don't want it,
残しちゃったらごめんねって
And saying "Sorry" if you leave leftovers—
…君のせいかしら？
...Is it your fault?
ひと口だけ ちょうだい もう一口だけ ちょうだいなんて
Saying "Give me just one bite, give me just one more bite"—
甘え上手ってずるいんじゃないの？
Isn't being so good at acting spoiled unfair?
ちょっとだけ ちょうだい ねえ出来たら全部 ちょうだいなんて
"Give me just a little bit, no wait, give me all of it"—
…君のせいかしら …私のせいかしら やっぱ君のせいかしら？
...Is it your fault? ...Is it my fault? No, is it your fault after all?
はい、ということで みんな、にゃっはろー！
Yes, and with that, hello everyone, Nya-hello!
はい、ということで 本日の主演、さくらみこですー！
Yes, and with that, today's star is Sakura Miko!
えーどう？どうみんな？どうだった？かわいかった？
Um, how was it, everyone? How did you like it? Was it cute?
ありがとうみんなー！
Thank you everyone!
はい、ということで 皆さん こちら、あ、こっち、こちらのね、さくらみこ生誕祭で たくさん つぶやいてくれてますか？
Yes, and with that, everyone, here—ah, over here—have you been tweeting a lot for Sakura Miko's Birthday Festival?
おぱちぱちありがとう！
Clap clap, thank you!
にゃっはろー、海外からも、せきゅー、ありがとう！
Nya-hello, from overseas too, thank you!
うわ、かわいかった！ ありがとう！ うまっ、うまうまうま
Wow, so cute! Thank you! So yummy, yummy yummy!
見て、このねステージもね、めちゃくちゃね、あの巫女仕様にステージできまして、本当にありがとうございます！
Look, this stage too, it's customized in Miko style, thank you so much!
ということで、このあとは ゲストパート、ゲストパートがありますので、みなさん 最後まで絶対見に、ね、み、見てってね！
So, after this, there's a guest part, so everyone, be sure to watch all the way to the end, okay, watch it!
それじゃあ、ゲストパート、レッツゴー！
Well then, guest part, let's go!
思い通りにいかないことだらけ どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
Full of things that don't go as planned, self-loathing with nothing I can do
八百万の痛みや悲しみから 逃げ込める場所を探してる
Searching for a place to run away from millions of pains and sorrows
いっそ岩の間に引きこもって 月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
Might as well hole up between the rocks, ignoring the moon and sun to sleep
生まれてきたちことの理由なんて知らない わかんないよ でもそんな風に思えるってことは
I don't know the reason I was born, I don't get it—but being able to feel that way
君がもっともっと素敵になれる力があるって教えてるんだよ
Teaches us that you have the power to become even more wonderful.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに 誰だって地球を愛している
That's right, at the gods' will, as they say, anyone loves the Earth.
飲めや歌えや どんちゃん騒ぎ たまにはそんなのもいいね
Drink and sing, make a wild racket, sometimes that's fine too!
思い通りにいかないことばかり どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
Things never go my way, I'm hopelessly self-loathing,
八百万の痛みや悲しみから逃げ込める場所を探してる
searching for a place to escape from countless pains and sorrows.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに 誰だって地球を愛してる
That's right, just at god's mercy, as commanded, everyone loves the earth!
飲み合え歌えや ドンチャン騒ぎ たまにゃそんなのもいいね
Drink and sing, have a wild party, that's nice once in a while.
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も なんだけん地球を愛してる
That's right, north and south, right and left, we all love the earth in our own way,
泥んこだけど 歩いて行ける まだまだ先は長いさ
even though we're muddy, we can keep walking, and we still have a long way to go.
八百万の痛みや悲しみから 逃げ込める場所を探してる
searching for a place to escape from countless pains and sorrows.
いっそ岩の間に引きこもって 月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
I might as well pull into a crevice in the rocks and sleep, ignoring the moon and sun.
泥んこだけど 歩いて行ける まだまだ先は長いさ
even though we're muddy, we can keep walking, and we still have a long way to go.
ただ正しい人でいたいだけ きっと誰もがそう願っているけど
All I desire is to be a fair person, and there's no doubt everyone else does too.
八百万の心の醜さに 苦しめられる毎日さ
Tormented daily by the eight million uglinesses of the heart.
僕が生きてきたこと 奇跡といえば聞こえはいいけど
The fact that I was born, calling it a miracle sounds nice,
それはきっと偶然にすぎなくて やっぱり意味なんてないさ
but it's surely just a coincidence, and after all, it has no meaning.
でも例えば君に意地悪をする奴がいるなら それは君にとってとても素敵な人だって教えてるんだよ
But if there's someone teasing you, it's teaching you that they're a wonderful person to you.
奇跡といえば聞こえはいいけど それはきっと偶然にすぎなくて
Calling it a miracle sounds nice, but it's surely just a coincidence...
本当に好きでなくて やっぱりいらないなんてないさ
But saying it's not truly loved and unnecessary isn't true at all.
でも例えば君に意地悪をする奴がいるなら
But if there's someone teasing you,
それは君にとってとても素敵な人だって教えてるんだよ
it's teaching you that they're a wonderful person to you.
やるしかない
We just have to do it!
いるならそれは君にとってとても素敵な人だって教えてるんだよ
If they're there, it teaches you they're a wonderful person to you!
そうさ神のまにまに 仰せのままに 誰だって地球を愛してる
That's right, just at god's mercy, as commanded, everyone loves the earth!
僕が笑って君も笑えば 許せないことなんてないよ
If I laugh and you laugh too, there's nothing that can't be forgiven.
そうさ僕も女の子 恋しがるとき そんなふうに地球をまわってる
That's right, I'm a girl too, wanting to fall in love, spinning the earth just like that.
泥んこだけど 歩いて行ける まだまだ先は長いさ
Even though we're muddy, we can walk on, there's still a long way to go.
孤独に大切なものなんて 赤く下らないことの中にあるよ
Things truly precious are found within trivial, foolish things.
時にはみんなでバカ騒ぎ 裸足でおどりでおうわらい
Sometimes everyone makes a fool of themselves, dancing barefoot and laughing loudly.
そうさ神のまにまに 仰せのままに まとめて自分を愛してるよ
That's right, just at god's mercy, as commanded, loving myself all together!
鏡をみてめぐらうよ もうわかるでしょ みんなあせのすうひかりだ
Looking in the mirror and wandering, you understand already, everyone's sweat is light.
そうさ神のまにまに 仰せのままに みんなありがとう やっぱ地球を愛してる
That's right, just at god's mercy, as commanded, thank you everyone, after all I love the earth!
花の大きさを 大きな花を 天まで届くくらいのラララ...
The size of flowers, huge flowers, reaching up to the heavens, la la la...
失敗だって Good night... 今日もまたまたやらかして
Even if it's a failure, good night... Making mistakes again today,
言い訳してる たまにはつけど 少し眠くなり まぶた落ちたら
making excuses, though sometimes... Getting a little sleepy, when my eyelids drop,
おふとんが幸せくれるの ふかふかで いつもありがとう
the futon gives me happiness. Thank you always for being fluffy,
包まれて うれしいな 夢へとゆっくり進みましょう
I'm so happy wrapped up in it. Let's slowly move on toward dreams!
今日もまたまたやらかして 言い訳してる たまにはつけど 少し眠くなり...
Making mistakes again today, making excuses, getting a little sleepy...
すこしねむくなり まぶた落ちたら おふとんがしあわせくれるの
When my eyelids drop, the futon gives me happiness.
おふとんが幸せくれるの ふかふかでいつもありがとう
The futon gives me happiness, thank you as always for being fluffy!
包まれて うれしいな 夢へとゆっくり進みましょう
I'm so happy wrapped up in it. Let's slowly move on toward dreams!
重力がなくなる わいわいごきげんだぜ すーすかぴー
Gravity disappears, yay, I'm in a good mood, zzz...
失敗だって Good night 寝逃げする事も悪くないよね
Even if it's a failure, good night. Running away into sleep isn't so bad!
失敗だって Good night... なにげすすることもないから
Even if it's a failure, good night...
悪くないよね きっと目が覚めて 忘れちゃうみんな
It's not bad, surely when I wake up, everyone will forget.
目が覚めて 忘れちゃうみんな 失敗だって Don't mind 朝のまぶしさに
When I wake up, everyone will forget. Even if it's a failure, don't mind the morning brightness!
失敗だって Don't mind 朝のまぶしさに 消えてしまえばいいな 新しい一日でリセット！
Even if it's a failure, don't mind, I hope it disappears in the morning brightness, reset with a brand new day!
新しい 一日でリセット！
Reset with a brand new day!
起きてぽやぽや手探りで時計を探す びっくりしたなんで誰か起こしてよ
Waking up fuzzy, groping for the clock, surprised, why, someone wake me up!
間に合わないよ おふとんが...
I won't make it in time, the futon was...
失敗だって Good night
A mistake? Good night.
今日もまたまた 言い訳してる
Today I'm making excuses again.
ため息などつけば 少し眠くなり
If I sigh, I get a little sleepy,
まぶた落ちたら おふとんが幸せくれるの
and when my eyelids drop, my futon brings me bliss.
ふかふかで いつもありがとう
So fluffy, thank you as always,
包まれてうれしいな
I'm so happy wrapped up in it.
夢へとゆっくり ゆっくり進みましょ
Slowly, slowly heading into a dream,
重力がなくなる
gravity disappears.
わーい ごきげんだ すーすかぴー zzz
Yay, I'm in a good mood, zzz...
失敗だって Good night
A mistake? Good night.
寝逃げする事も 悪くないよね
Running away by sleeping isn't bad either.
きっと目が覚めて 忘れちゃうみんな
I'm sure when I wake up, everyone will forget.
失敗だって Don't mind
A mistake? Don't mind.
朝のまぶしさにとけてしまえばいいな
I hope it dissolves in the morning brightness.
新しい一日でリセット！
Reset with a brand new day!
起きてぽややら 手探りで
Waking up dazed, feeling around
時計を探す びっくりした なんて
for the clock, 'How surprising,' I thought,
誰か起こしてよ 間に合わないよ
'Someone wake me up, I won't make it!'
おふとんが幸せすぎたね
My futon was just too blissful.
慌ててり ざっそく着替えたら
Panicking, as I quickly got changed,
閉まらないスカートの
the skirt wouldn't close—
ファスナー あせればあせるほど 最悪ね
the zipper, the more I rushed, the worse it got.
布がはさまった えーん どうしてるの
Fabric got caught, 'Oh no, what do I do?!'
ぷっぴかぷー ;; ;
Puppikapuu...
散々だった morning
What a disastrous morning.
(間奏)
Music playing...
余裕持ちなくちゃ こけすばかりで
I need to have some breathing room, I'm just stumbling.
もっとしっかりね 少しだけ凹む
I need to be firmer, getting a little down.
散々だった Don't mind
Disastrous? Don't mind.
靴をはきながら 外へ飛び出すの
Flying outside while putting on my shoes.
キラリいい天気 素敵だな がんばっちゃうね
Such lovely weather, wonderful, I'll do my best!
自慢なんて言わないで
Don't call it bragging.
早朝なんて釣らないで
Don't fish for compliments so early.
青春なんて知らないで
Don't talk about youth like you know it.
あせあせじりじり 何年生？
Hurry, hurry, step by step, what grade are you?
紹介なんて聞かないで
Don't ask for introductions.
想像なんて止めないで
Don't stop imagining.
Everyday, everyone! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
失敗だって Good night
A mistake? Good night.
寝逃げする事も 悪くないよね
Running away by sleeping isn't bad either.
きっと目が覚めて 忘れちゃうみんな
I'm sure when I wake up, everyone will forget.
失敗だって Don't mind
A mistake? Don't mind.
朝のまぶしさにとけてしまえばいいな
I hope it dissolves in the morning brightness.
新しい一日でリセット！
Reset with a brand new day!
ふかふかで ちゃっかりありがとう
So fluffy, opportunely thank you.
すかぴー すかぴー すか大きなちゃ
Sukapii sukapii, a big sukapii...
ぽややらで まったり行きたいな
I want to go at a leisurely, dazed pace.
娘寝そで あわててもうダッシュ
Even rushing in daughter's sleep wear, dash!
ぽややらで 娘寝そで
Leisurely in sleep wear...
ライアーダンス Sakura Miko × Shiranui Flare
[Title: Liar Dance]
奪った？それなんのことかしら
Stolen? Well, whatever do you mean by that?
知らんぷって 今日を重ねるの
Pretending not to know as days pile up.
誓った 他の誰でもない きみの前で
Promised, in front of you and nobody else.
愛のない愛 表明
A declaration of loveless love.
奪った？それなんのことかしら
Stolen? Well, whatever do you mean by that?
決め文句 演じ切るまさに
Playing out the punchline to perfection.
寝抱いて飼い込んだ想い出は
Memories embraced and harbored close
絡み合って 情を増してくの
intertwine and make these feelings grow.
なんだかんだ言うが ちょっと黙ってや
Say what you will, but shut up for a bit.
もうどれもこれも嘘に見えて仕舞い込んだんだ
Everything started looking like lies, so I hid it away.
どこにきみの逃げる場所が残ってる？
Is there anywhere left for you to run?
そう僕も悪できみも悪さ 理解してんだ
I knew we were both in the wrong, I understood.
1, 2 … 1, 2, 3
1, 2... 1, 2, 3
踊っちゃってライアー 膨らんじまったこの愛は
Dance, liar! This love that's grown so vast
針を刺して嘘に変えよう 「好き」と伝えちゃって
Pierce it with a needle, turn it to a lie, and say 'I love you'.
踊っちゃってライアー 膨らんじまったこの愛は
Dance, liar! This love that's grown so vast
針を刺して嘘に変えよう 「好き」と伝えちゃって
Pierce it with a needle, turn it to a lie, and say 'I love you'.
染まっちゃってライアー 薄まっちまったこの愛は
Soaked in it, liar! This love that's washed away
きみが全部飲み干してよ どこに行ったって
Drink it all down, no matter where you go.
もう異常だよ
It's completely abnormal.
奪った？それなんのことかしら
Stolen? Well, whatever do you mean by that?
知らんぷって 今日も重なるの
Pretending not to know as days pile up.
隠した 誰も触れないように
Hidden so that nobody can touch it.
渇くダンス 炭酸のメロディ
An arid dance, soda's melody.
「しまった！バレ……なんてことかしら？」
'Oh no! Busted... whatever could that mean?'
シラを切って何度間違えば
Feigning ignorance, how many times must I mess up
嵌まった底なんてない沼に
before realizing I'm drowning in a bottomless pit?
溺れたって気付くのですか？
(Have you even noticed you're drowning?)
奪った?それなんのことかしら
\"I stole it?\" \"No, I don't know what you're talking 'bout\"
知らんぷりって 今日を重ねるの
You bluff away with this charade that I can't figure out
誓った
My darling
他の誰でもない きみの前で
You cross your heart, and then you hope to die
愛のない愛 表明
So keep on lying to my face and see if I comply
奪った?それなんのことかしら
\"I stole it?\" \"No, I don't know what you're talking 'bout\"
決まり文句 演じ切るまさに
You speak clichés and reap the praise of all the fools in doubt
寝抱って飼い込んだ想い出は
My darling
絡み合って 情を増していくの
Why can't you see that there's no fooling me?
なんだかんだ言うが ちょっと黙ってや
Our love is much more of a mess than even you could be
もうどれもこれも嘘に見えて仕舞い込んだんだ
Blah, blah, blah, blah, do me a favor and shut up for now
どこにきみの逃げ場所が残ってる?
You think you sound clever, but 'cause I know better, you sound just too loud
そう僕も悪できみも悪さ
Try to escape and you'll see that you don't have a place left to hide
理解ってんだ
So speak of the devil, but know that you're summoning me to your side
踊っちゃってライアー
1, 2, 1, 2, 3
膨らんじゃったこの愛は
Dance away, you li-i-iar
針を刺して嘘に変えよう
Your loving burns like fi-i-ire
「好き」と逝っちゃって染まっちゃってライアー
Only you, only me, let's tear these vows to shreds and let death do us pa-a-art
薄まっちゃったこの愛は
Poison me, you li-i-iar
きみが全部飲み干してよ
Our love is old and ti-i-ired, so cover your nose and swallow me away
どこに行ったって もう異常だよ
I'll get into your vei-i-ins, and then we'll meet our end
奪った?それなんのことかしら
\"I stole it?\" \"No, I don't know what you're talking 'bout\"
知らんぷりって 今日も重なるの
You bluff away with this charade that I can't figure out
隠した誰も触れないように
It's hidden, it's tucked away somewhere that's safe and sound
渇くダンス 炭酸のメロディー
I hear you loud and clear, so baby, there's no need to shout
シラを切って何度間違うば
\"You got me!\" \"No wait, I've got no clue, what could you mean?\"
嵌まった底なんて無い沼に
Caught you again today, again you slip away from me
溺れたって気付くのですか?
You're sinking, digging your grave deeper and deeper down
誰も彼もきみのことを嘲笑っている
For all your talk, I see you're nothing but a helpless clown
もう僕もきみが嘘に見えて仕舞い込んだんだ
Everyone and my own mother is starting to make fun of you
だけどなぜかきみのことを想っている
'Cause nothing about all the lies that you tell yourself seem to sound true
そう僕も悪できみも悪さ 理解ってんだ
But in the end, you're the beautiful liar who's stolen my heart, oh
踊っちゃってライアー シェッドしてもう遅いの
You're just the devil, but I'm on your level, so drag me down now
すでに恋の共犯さ
1, 2, 1, 2, 3
戻れなくたって
Dance with me, you li-i-iar
エビバディ→解体!
Everybody, dismantle!
思い出に消しゴム!?あれっ。
Erasing memories with an eraser!? Oh, whoops.
ハイになる?廃になる?
Become high? Become obsolete?
はい、とは言えな~い!!!
“Yes”, can’t say that~!!!
お可視い世界 お菓子は消えしまい!?どうしよう
The visible world, sweets disappear!? What should I do?
“どうして!?”も “ああして!!”も
“Why!?” and “Like that!!” too,
君らしくないな?
Isn’t that like you?
そんな時代でいいよ
It’s okay in this kind of era
僕らまだ“ワンダー”信じているの ノ No? know!
We still believe in “wonder,” you know! No? know!
大人たちの鋭利(営利)な目盛(×メモリー)
The sharp (profit) scale of adults (× memory)
悩ましさぎしすぎて
It’s too much of a bother,
寄り目になってしまいそぅね!!
Seems like we’re getting cross-eyed!!
“どうして!?” “ああして!!”も
“Why!?” and “Like that!!” too,
「全部」だいすき!がいいじゃん!!
Isn’t it great to love “everything”!!
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの魂胆で
With the plot to make everyone, everyone smile,
宿敵(ライバル)逆境モンスター呼んだっていいじゃん!?
Isn’t it fine to summon arch-enemy (rival) adversity monsters!?
スットキョウでサイキョウなセカイを
With a eccentric and strongest world
どうにもこうにも救えない困難もいいじゃん!!
Isn’t it fine even if difficulties cannot be saved no matter what!!
みんなみんな救いちゃんお!のポーズで
With the pose of saving everyone, everyone!
ちょっとやそっとじゃ壊れない笑顔どうしぶ?
How about a smile that won’t crash easily no matter what!
100回オチても不気疑は鳥乱さない
Even if we fall 100 times, the mystery won't be flustered
ワンワンで ツーカーで スリー フォー エビバディ ショウタイム!
One-one, two-to-kar, three, four, everybody showtime!
デモ デモ センセイ! 答案用紙は散々!! うわー!
But, but, teacher! The answer sheet is terrible!! Wow!
ハイ終わる?ファイナル? 0点(エンド)じゃないなら、OK!
High ends? Final? If it’s not 0 points (end), OK!
マルバツ全部 一切合切ウチュウしよう!
Let’s cosmos all circles and crosses completely!
正解も不正解も 大切なメモリー
Both correct answers and incorrect answers are precious memories
つまづく日もあるよ
There are days when you trip,
君はまだ“ワンダー”否定しているの、の ノ No? know!
Are you still denying “wonder”? No? know!
解体(バラ)す前に きいてよ 待って!
Before dismantling, listen to me, wait!
トンガリすぎちゃう斜(しゃか)いに
Into the overly pointy society,
ツッコんで、トンで、もう一回(もういいかい)!?
Tsukkon de, ton de, one more time (moo ii kai)!?
成功失敗も「全部」だいすき!でいいじゃん!!
Isn’t it great to love success and failure “everything”!!
みんなみんなウチュウしよう?の魂胆で
With the plot to let’s cosmos together, everyone!
だってだって君ももっと笑えたじゃん!?
Because, because you used to smile more, didn't you!?
スットキョウでサイキョウな僕らは
Eccentric and strongest us,
まだまだ消さないで!?未来はここからじゃん!!
Don't erase it yet!? The future starts right from here!!
みんなみんな一緒しよう!のポーズで
With the pose of letting’s be together, everyone!
ちょっとやそっとじゃ崩れない笑顔どうしぶ!
How about a smile that won’t collapse easily no matter what!
100回トンだトンテモお菓子いセカイ
If you fly 100 times, a bizarrely sweet world
ツッコんで、トンで、ドッカンで、ツンでもう一回!
Tsukkon de, ton de, dokkan de, tsunde mou ikkai!
ツッコんで、トンで、ドッカンで、ツンでもういいかい!?
Tsukkon de, ton de, dokkan de, tsunde mou ii kai!?
スウィーツワンダフル シンチュウワオ!
Sweets wonderful, shin-chuu wao!
エビバディ→解体!
Everybody, dismantle!
思い出に消しゴム!?あれっ。
Erasing memories with an eraser!? Oh, whoops.
ハイになる?廃になる?
Become high? Become obsolete?
はい、とは言えな~い!!!
“Yes”, can’t say that~!!!
お可視い世界 お菓子は消えしまい!?どうしよう
The visible world, sweets disappear!? What should I do?
“どうして!?”も “ああして!!”も
“Why!?” and “Like that!!” too,
君らしくないな?
Isn’t that like you?
そんな時代でいいよ
It’s okay in this kind of era
僕らまだ“ワンダー”信じているの ノ No? know!
We still believe in “wonder,” you know! No? know!
大人たちの鋭利(営利)な目盛(×メモリー)
The sharp (profit) scale of adults (× memory)
悩ましさぎしすぎて
It’s too much of a bother,
寄り目になってしまいそぅね!!
Seems like we’re getting cross-eyed!!
“どうして!?” “ああして!!”も
“Why!?” and “Like that!!” too,
「全部」だいすき!がいいじゃん!!
Isn’t it great to love “everything”!!
みんなみんな笑っちゃえの魂胆で
With the plot to make everyone, everyone smile,
宿敵(ライバル)逆境モンスター呼んだっていいじゃん!?
Isn’t it fine to summon arch-enemy (rival) adversity monsters!?
スットキョウでサイキョウなセカイを
With a eccentric and strongest world
どうにもこうにも救えない困難もいいじゃん!!
Isn’t it fine even if difficulties cannot be saved no matter what!!
みんなみんな救いちゃんお!のポーズで
With the pose of saving everyone, everyone!
ちょっとやそっとじゃ壊れない笑顔どうしぶ?
How about a smile that won’t crash easily no matter what!
100回オチても不気疑は鳥乱さない
Even if we fall 100 times, the mystery won't be flustered
ワンワンで ツーカーで スリー フォー エビバディ ショウタイム!
One-one, two-to-kar, three, four, everybody showtime!
会いたいな 会えないな
I miss you, can't see you,
切ないな この気持ち
breaks my heart, these feelings do.
言えないの 言いたいの
Can't tell you, really want to,
チャンス逃してばかり
I keep missing my chance.
だって だって 翼広げ二人で
'Cause see, I wanna spread our wings together,
空をマラソン 夢をユニゾンしたい
do a marathon around the sky, and unify our dreams!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
See? Catch you catch you catch me, wait,
こっちをむいて スキだといって
look at me, say you like me,
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
yeah, nice to meet you good to see you, definitely.
私の想い あなたのハートに飛んで飛んで飛んでゆけ
My feelings for you fly, fly, fly to your heart!
迷わない
I don't hesitate.
たまにね なくなっちゃう
Sometimes it runs out,
身体のバッテリー
my body's battery does.
あなたの笑顔で いつも充電満タン パワー爆発しちゃえ
Your smile always fully charges it up—explode it with power!
お願い お願い
Pretty please, pretty please,
まずは お友達から
I wanna start out as friends,
笑って 見つめて 楽しい毎日にしたい
then laugh, and stare, and make every day fun.
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
See? Catch you catch you catch me, absolutely,
運命だって お似合いだって
say it's destiny, say we fit together perfectly,
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
yeah, nice to meet you good to see you, definitely.
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で一番一番一番一番
I'm second to none. Of everyone in the world, I'm the most, most, most, most
コ・イ・シ・テル
in love with you.
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
See? Catch you catch you catch me, wait,
こっちをむいて スキだといって
look at me, say you like me,
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
yeah, nice to meet you good to see you, definitely.
私の想い あなたのハートに飛んで飛んで飛んでゆけ
My feelings for you fly, fly, fly to your heart!
迷わない
I don't hesitate.
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
See? Catch you catch you catch me, absolutely,
運命だって お似合いだって
say it's destiny, say we fit together perfectly,
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
yeah, nice to meet you good to see you, definitely.
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で一番一番一番一番
I'm second to none. Of everyone in the world, I'm the most, most, most, most
コ・イ・シ・テル
in love with you.
手のひらに掴んだ約束は
The promise I grasped in the palm of my hand
永遠に消えない宝もの
is a treasure that will never fade away.
いつか見上げた空の彼方に
To the other side of the sky we looked up to one day,
僕らの明日へと導く Future Star
guiding us toward our tomorrow—Future Star.
君と共に流した涙 まるで夜を駆ける流星で
The tears we shed together were like a shooting star racing through the night,
願い事が叶うのならば ひとつ大事なモノを守るよ
and if wishes come true, I will protect one precious thing.
奇跡は偶然じゃない 努力の結晶で
Miracles aren't a coincidence; they're the fruit of our hard work.
どんな暗闇にも
No matter how dark it is,
美しい夢はあるよ
there's always a beautiful dream.
もっと前へ進もう 諦めない心
Let's push further ahead, with a heart that never gives up,
君とならば頑張れる
if I'm with you, I can do my best.
無駄なことはないよ 上を向いて笑おう
Nothing is in vain, look up and smile,
一度きりの時間だから
because this is a once-in-a-lifetime moment.
忘れないよ笑顔 どんなつらい道も
I won't forget to smile, no matter how painful the path,
いつも君がそばにいる
you're always by my side.
辿り着いた先に 何が待っていようと
No matter what awaits us at our destination,
明日を照らす絆は Future Star
the bond illuminating tomorrow is our Future Star.
くじけそうなひとりの夜は いつも君の笑顔を思うの
On lonely nights when I might break, I always think of your smile.
なぜか胸が熱くなるから 少し前を向いて歩けるよ
For some reason my chest feels warm, so I can walk looking slightly ahead.
仲間はかけがえのない
Friends are irreplaceable,
僕らの青春
our youth.
二度と戻れないから
Since we can never return,
大切な歌があった
we had a precious song.
ずっと前へ進もう 光の果てまでも
Let's keep moving forward, even to the edge of the light,
君とならば越えられる
if I'm with you, we can overcome it.
怖くなんないよ だから強く笑おう
There's nothing to be scared of, so let's smile strongly.
涙拭うおまじない
A spell to wipe away tears.
迷わないで行くよ 長く険しい道も
I'll go without hesitating, down the long, rugged road.
いつも君がそばにいる
You're always by my side.
どんな悲しい今日も どんな苦しい今日も
No matter how sad today is, no matter how painful today is,
明日はきっと輝く Destiny
tomorrow will surely shine like Destiny.
もっと前へ進もう 諦めない心
Let's push further ahead, with a heart that never gives up,
君とならば頑張れる
if I'm with you, I can do my best.
無駄なことはないよ 上を向いて笑おう
Nothing is in vain, look up and smile,
一度きりの時間だから
because this is a once-in-a-lifetime moment.
忘れないよ笑顔 どんなつらい道も
I won't forget to smile, no matter how painful the path,
いつも君がそばにいる
you're always by my side.
辿り着いた先に 何が待っていようと
No matter what awaits us at our destination,
明日を照らす絆は Future Star
the bond illuminating tomorrow is our Future Star.
手のひらに掴んだ約束は
The promise grasped in the palm of our hands
永遠に消えない宝もの
is a treasure that will never fade away.
いつか見上げた空の彼方に
Far off in the sky we once looked up at,
僕らの明日へと導く Future Star
guiding us toward our tomorrow—Future Star.
よっしゃー！
Alright!
よっしゃよっしゃよっしゃー！
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
よっしゃー！
Let's go!
すいちゃんが来てくれました！
Suisei-chan has come to join us!
皆さんこんにちは！星街すいせい です！ V！V！
Hello everyone! I'm Hoshimachi Suisei! V! V!
すいちゃん！
Suisei-chan!
今日もかわいい！
You're so cute today too!
かわいい！ かわいい！
So cute! So cute!
え、きん、しなくていい？
Wait, do I not need to be nervous?
かわいいー！ かわいいー！
So cute! So cute!
あのね、本日は何の日でしょう？
You know, what day is today?
え？
Eh?
えっ、今日何日だっけ？ 3月の…5日！
Wait, what date is today? March... 5th!
3月の5日！
March 5th!
えー、3ごの日！
Um, Miko's Day!
違う！
Wrong!
違うの？ え、違うの？ 違う！
Wrong? Huh, wrong? Wrong!
あ、違うのか。えー待て、じゃあ、3と5だから… みとしの日だ！
Ah, wrong. Wait, then since it's 3 and 5... It's Mitoshi Day!
違う！
Wrong!
なんで、なんでスーッと行くんだよ！
Why, why are you going along with it so smoothly?!
あれ？ なんか、なんでここに呼ばれてるんだ？
Huh? Wait, why am I even called here?
なんか、あれ？ なんて書いてあるのあれ、あれあれ… ば、ば… ば… ば…
Wait, what does that say over there? Ba... ba... ba...
読めるじゃん！ 読める読める！ 読めるあれ！ バースデー・パーティ！
You can read it! You can read it! You can read that! Birthday Party!
バースデー・パーティ！ バースデー・パーティ！
Birthday Party! Birthday Party!
あれれ？
Huh?
それは？
What's that?
え？
Eh?
じゃん！さくらみこのはお誕生日！
Tada! It's Sakura Miko's birthday!
うわあ、そうなんだ！
Whoa, is that right?!
なんで知らんの？
Why didn't you know?
知らなかっ…あれ、だってなんか
I didn't... Wait, because like
あの、依頼書に書いてなかったけど。
it wasn't written in the request form.
え、依頼書に書いてある！依頼書に！
Eh, it is in the request form! In the request form!
あれ、あれ？そうなんだ！おめでとう、おめでとう！
Wait, really?! Congratulations, congratulations!
ありがとう。なんかそれも渡せって言われてたもんが。
Thank you. They told me to hand that over too.
あ、あった、あったよ、ほら。
Ah, there it is, look.
なに？
What?
え、なんか用意してきてくれたの？
Eh, did you prepare something for me?
落とす、落としちゃう、これ。
I'm gonna drop it, I'm gonna drop this!
大丈夫？大丈夫かな、それ。
Are you okay? Will that be okay?
お、すごっ！
Oh, amazing!
大丈夫それ？
Is that okay?
お、落ちる！落ちる！フラフラする！
Woah, it's falling! It's falling! It's wobbling!
あ、みこちこれ、みこちへのケーキじゃ！おわあああ！
Ah, Miko-chi, this is a cake for Miko-chi! Waaaaah!
おい！
Hey!
え、どうしたの？
Eh, what's wrong?
おかしいだろ！
That's weird!
いや、そりゃ誕生日とゆえばケーキ投げでしょ。
Well, I mean, a birthday means throwing cake, right?
ケーキ投げ？すんじゃねえよ！おい、お前正気かよ！
Throwing cake? Don't do that! Hey, are you out of your mind?!
え、いや、そうそうそう、今のさ
Eh, no, right, right, right, that was
張りぼてで、もう一回ちゃんとするだって。ほら、これは本物だよ！
just paper-mache, let's do it properly again. Look, this is the real one!
本当かな？
Is that true?
本当だよ。
It's true.
本当かな？
Is that true?
おお、ちょっと、ちょっと！
Whoa, wait, wait!
おお、ちょっと！お、危ない！
Whoa, wait! Woah, watch out!
フラフラする！
It's wobbling!
あ、みこち！
Ah, Miko-chi!
あ、待って待って待って待って待って待って待って！あ、待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait! Ah, wait!
あ、食べきりました。
Ah, I ate it all up.
めちゃっ食った。
I ate so much.
ほい、皿投げる。
Here, throwing the plate.
一気に食うと気持ち悪くなっちゃうんだね。
Eating it all at once makes you feel sick, huh?
え、そうだろうね。
Eh, I suppose so.
あ、でも、ありがとうございました。
But thank you very much.
おいしかったね。
It was delicious, right?
おいしかった！
It was delicious!
よかった、よかった。スタッフが作りました！
Good, good. The staff made it!
ありがとう、スタッフ。
Thank you, staff.
ありがとう、スタッフ！すいちゃんはね、
Thank you, staff! Suisei-chan,
渡せって言われただけです。
was just told to hand it over.
え？ユーザーじゃないよ！ビジネスレジェンドでしょ、
Eh? Not a user! It's business legend,
ビジネスレジェンド！
business legend!
あ、なんかそういえば、
Ah, come to think of it,
らしいですね。YouTubeライブでは、みこめっとと揃うのは初めてらしいですね。
it seems. Apparently, this is the first time MikoMeto is together on a YouTube live.
あ！
Ah!
いや、なんかこのメンツな、そんなに珍しいものではないけど。
Well, this lineup isn't that rare though.
え、そうなんですよ。ちょっとね、お仕事とか、お仕事とかお仕事とかお仕事で、
Eh, that's right. Because of work, work, work, and work,
お仕事とかお仕事とかいつもありがとうございます。
thank you as always.
あ、どうも。
Ah, thanks.
よくね、ライブさせてもらってます、2人で。また誘ってください。
We often get to live perform together. Please invite us again.
ぜひ！
Definitely!
あ、じゃそっか！
Ah, then I see!
はい、こうやってね、普通にね、コラボしたりするのは、
Doing collaborations like this normally,
そうだね。お初？
is that right. For the first time?
お初ですね。
For the first time.
いやあ！
Yay!
ええ！嬉しいなあ。
Yay! I'm so happy.
嬉しい、みんな。
Are you happy, everyone?
いぇーい！
Yay!
なんか最近需要が高まってきたらしいよ。
Apparently the demand has been rising lately.
何が？
What is?
みこめっと。
MikoMeto.
ふっ、ふふふふ！
Heh, hahaha!
そっか！
I see!
なんかね、ファンアートとかね増えてきてね。
Like, fan art and stuff has been increasing.
すごいらしいよ。
It seems amazing.
嬉しいか。あ、こびとこ、こびとこ。
Are you happy? Ah, do the pose, do the pose.
みこめっとね。
Mikomet, right.
やっぱ客と一緒に撮ったりもする？
Do you take pictures with the audience too?
じゃ、よろしくしてもらって。カメラさん！
So, please do that, and camera-san!
みこめっと！みこめっと！
Mikomet, Mikomet!
かわいい！
Cute!
かわいいね！
So cute!
よろこび、あ、喜んでる、ほら。
Rejoic-, ah, they're rejoicing, look.
あ、どういうこと？
Ah, what do you mean?
おいおいおい！おいおい！
Hey hey hey! Hey hey!
やっぱ嬉しいんだみんなね、みこめっと。
Everyone's happy, right, Mikomet.
嬉しいの、みんな。
Are you happy, everyone?
きゃっぴー、きゃっぴー。
Cappy, cappy.
なんかポーズとろう。
Let's strike a pose.
え、ないよ？
Eh, I don't have one?
え、こびのよ、すいちゃんの。
Eh, Kobinoyo, Suisei's.
こ、こ、こ、いいじゃん！
Co, co, co, that's good!
お仕事なら、お仕事なら。
If it's work, if it's work.
ああ、かわいい！
Ah, cute!
いいじゃないですか。
Isn't that nice?
これは換気したね。
We ventilated this, huh.
はい、これは湧きましたね、みなさん。
Yes, everyone got hyped about this.
いや、あれはあの、ケーキ、ケーキを取りたい。
No, that was, um, I want to take the cake, cake.
またおいしそうまだ。ケーキはもうあんたが食べてしまった。
It still looks delicious. You already ate the cake.
え、予備があるんですか？よかった、よかった！
Eh, is there a spare? Good, good!
はいはいはい、予備、予備、予備！予備予備予備！
Yes yes yes, spare, spare, spare! Spare spare spare!
じゃあ、このステージ見せながらやる？
Then, shall we do it while showing the stage?
なるほど。
I see.
うん。
Yeah.
はい、じゃカメラさん。
Yes, then camera-san.
ケーキがこんな感じ。
The cake is like this.
よし！
Yosh!
はい、か、か、かわいく、かわいいポーズ。
Yes, cu-, cu-, cute, cute pose.
かわいいポーズ。
Cute pose.
え、すごい！
Eh, amazing!
かわいいかも。
Might be cute.
いい、いいアングル。いいアングル。
Good, good angle. Good angle.
ありがとう、すいちゃん。
Thank you, Suisei-chan.
いい、上手よ。
Good, skilled.
プルプル、プルプルしてる！
It's wobbling, wobbling!
いいってことよ！支えてるぞ！
That's what I mean! Supporting it!
大丈夫か？落ちる！落ちる！
Is it okay? It's falling! Falling!
落とすんじゃないよ、食べ物を！
Don't drop the food!
食べ物じゃない、あれ張りぼてだから。
It's not food, that was paper-mache.
はい、ということでね、
Yes, and so,
ま、すいちゃんに来てもらいましたと。
well, we had Suisei-chan come over.
本当にどうもありがとうございますね。
Thank you truly very much.
いやいやいや、では定時なので帰らせていただきます。
No, no, no, since it's quitting time, I'll be leaving.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
バイバイ、またねー！
Bye-bye, see you again!
ということで、定時で帰ってしまったということで。
And so, having left at quitting time.
じゃあ、みこちゃんもね、お着替えしてこようと思います。みんな待っててねー！
Well, Miko-chan too, I'm going to go change clothes. Everyone wait for me!
待っててねー！
Wait for me!
言いかけた言葉を飲み込んで
I swallowed the words I started to say,
あれっ不具合かな
Huh, is there a glitch?
らしく進もう
Let's move forward just like ourselves.
GOOD DAY めざましより
GOOD DAY, earlier than my alarm clock.
早起き の SUNNY DAY
An early-riser's SUNNY DAY.
今日は いつも より も
Today, more than always,
ちょっと おしゃれ 頑張った
I tried a bit harder to look nice!
なのに 全然
And yet, totally...
君 は 全然 気づか ない で よそ見 し て る ん だ
You're not noticing at all, looking away elsewhere!
知ら ない 乙女 心
A maiden's heart you know nothing about—
教えて あげる
I'll teach it to you!
君 が 好き ！ 素直 に なっ て
I like you! If I could just be honest
言え たら どんな に so happy
and say it, how happy I'd be!
溢れ 出す この 愛 は 甘い だけ で は あり ませ ん ！
This overflowing love isn't just sweet!
明日 が 今日 より 輝い て
May tomorrow shine brighter than today,
幸せ に なれ ます よう に
and may I be happy!
ちょっと くらい つよがり な ところ も 許し て ください
Please forgive my occasional bit of bravado,
逃げ て ちゃ ダメ 避けて ちゃ ダメ
Don't run away, don't avoid it—
後悔 なんて し たく ない
I don't want any regrets!
LETS GO HAPPY らしく進もう
LETS GO HAPPY, let's move forward just like ourselves!
なんで！？ ついてなくて
Why?! Nothing's going right—
へこんじゃう RAINY DAY
A depressing RAINY DAY.
お気に入りの靴 水たまりガッカリ！
My favorite shoes, what a disappointment in a puddle!
なのに 突然 君 が 突然
And yet, suddenly, you suddenly
振り返っ た その 笑顔 で
turned around with that smile,
あつく なっ て ゆく 頬 に 気づか ない で ね
and my cheeks grew warm—please don't notice!
君 の 手 と 手 が 触れ合っ て 伝わっ てる よ もう my sweet
Our hands touching, it's already getting across, my sweet!
溢れ出すこの愛を甘い果実に育てたい！
I want to nurture this overflowing love into a sweet fruit!
今日うまくいなくたって明日から変われるように
Even if today didn't go well, so I can change starting tomorrow,
ちょっとだけ弱気でも私を照らしてください
Please shine on me even when I'm feeling a bit timid,
涙ふいて上を向いて
Wipe your tears, look up,
止まってなんていられない
You can't afford to just stop!
LETS GO HAPPY らしく進もう
LETS GO HAPPY, let's move forward just like ourselves!
昨日までの自分にさよなら
Say goodbye to the self up until yesterday,
明日は(きっと)明日の(もっと)太陽が照らすよ
Tomorrow, (surely) tomorrow's (even more) sun will shine!
君 が 好き ！ 素直 に なっ て
I like you! If I could just be honest
言え たら どんな に so happy
and say it, how happy I'd be!
溢れ 出す この 愛 は 甘い だけ で は あり ませ ん ！
This overflowing love isn't just sweet!
明日 が 今日 より 輝い て
May tomorrow shine brighter than today,
幸せ に なれ ます よう に
and may I be happy!
ちょっと くらい つよがり な ところ も 許し て ください
Please forgive my occasional bit of bravado,
逃げ て ちゃ ダメ 避けて ちゃ ダメ
Don't run away, don't avoid it—
後悔 なんて し たく ない
I don't want any regrets!
LETS GO HAPPY らしく進もう
LETS GO HAPPY, let's move forward just like ourselves!
銀河の隅で 惑星はグルグル回る
In a corner of the Milky Way, the planets go round and round.
電波の記録 エコーが返ってきた
A radio wave recording, an echo returned.
これで何回だ
How many times does this make it?
遠くの宇宙で あなたに恋をしたんだ
In the distant cosmos, I fell in love with you.
届かないこと 理解しているのに
Even though I understand that it won't reach you...
あああなたに逢いたいなって気持ちがループ・ループする
Ah, "I want to meet you"—my feelings loop, they loop.
頭がどうにかなりそうだ それ以外交わさない
I feel like I'm losing my mind, I can't exchange anything else.
ああいますぐ逢いたいなって来る日もループ・ループする
Ah, "I want to meet you right now"—the coming days loop too, they loop.
この周回軌道上にあなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbital path,
そこに大体、愛があるだけ
There, generally, is only love.
声を辿って 何光年だ
Following your voice, how many light-years away
延長線に消えてゆく
fading along the extension line
このままパッと忘れられたら
If I could just forget it all like this
楽だろうなあ
how easy it would be
触れられないのに見えてしまって
Even though I can't touch you, I see you
どうしようもないや
there's nothing I can do
近くて遠いあなただ
You're close yet so far
理解してるよ
I understand that
ああ それでも会いたいなって
Ah, even so, I want to see you
何度もループ・ループする
looping over and over
心があなたで鳴っている
My heart is ringing with you
それだけが確かだ それだけでいいよ
that alone is certain, that alone is all I need
ああ 星が回るように
Ah, just as the stars turn
ぼくらはずっとループする
we keep looping forever
想いが軌跡を描いている
My feelings are drawing an orbit
あなただけを追うよ
chasing only you
ああ いま すぐ 会いたいなって
Ah, right now I want to see you
命がループ・ループする
my life loops and loops
この周回軌道上に あなたがいなくても
Even if you're not on this orbit
それ以外思えない
I can't think of anything else
そこに大体、愛が在るだけ
There, generally, is only love
ということで みんなどうですか
And so, everyone, how is it?
この髪型可愛いでしょう
This hairstyle is cute, right?
イエーイ みんなありがとう
Yay! Thank you everyone!
ありがとう
Thank you!
ということで みなさんここまでやってきましたけども
And so, everyone, we've made it this far,
もう後半戦に突入しております
but we've already entered the second half!
みなさんどうですか
How is everyone?
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
みんななんか声援がなくなってるよ、可愛いすか？
Everyone's cheers are disappearing, is it because I'm cute?
って言ってないよ、まあ可愛いからね、みこは。
I didn't say that, well, because Miko is cute.
はいということで、このパートはね、ちょっと短いんで、
Right, so, this part is a bit short,
急ぎ足で皆さんにこの後2曲ぐらいね、すごい歌ってくれたりダンスしたら嬉しいだろうなって曲があるんですけど
so I want to quickly tell you about the next two songs where we can sing and dance together...
はい、さくらみこ誕生日記念2022
Yes, Sakura Miko's Birthday Commemoration 2022
誕生日記念フルセットが販売します！やったー！
Birthday Commemoration full set is now on sale! Yay!
はい、じゃあこちら、とどーん！
Yes, so here, ta-da!
まずですね、ラバーマット、ビッグシルエットTシャツ、キーホルダー、みこぴのぬいぐるみやったー！そしてポストカード。
First, the rubber mat, oversized silhouette T-shirt, keychains, MikoPi plushie, yay! And a postcard.
はい、こちらは、おるだん先生が描いてくれました！
Yes, this was drawn by Ordan-sensei!
この誕生日パーティの後みたいな、みこのラバースマットです。やったー！可愛い！絶対買うー！
This rubber mat features Miko after her birthday party. Yay! So cute! I'm totally buying it!
そしてみんな見て！Tシャツだよ！
And everyone look! It's a T-shirt!
こちらをですね、大川ぶくぶ先生に描いていただきましたよ！
This was drawn by Ohkawa Bukubu-sensei!
わあ、これはもう普段使いができるな！ここがね、「にゃはろー」って言います。
Wow, you can totally wear this everyday! Here it says "Nyahallo".
めっちゃ可愛いよね！これめっちゃ可愛いよね！
It's super cute, right! Everyone buy this!
続いてこちら！これはみこぴ、金時、おじとちとね、みこが描きました。
Next is this! This was drawn by Miko: MikoPi, Kintoki, and Ojitochi.
こちらキーホルダーになってます！みんな買ってね！
These are keyholders! Everyone buy them!
手描き、
Hand-drawn,
そして
and
こちら！ ドン！
this! Ta-da!
ずにゃにゃんこぴーのぬいぐるみが出たよ、たやたやたやたや！
The 35P Neko-pi plushie is out! Yay, yay, yay!
めっちゃ嬉しい！ めっちゃ可愛いよ、ね！
I'm so happy! It's so cute, right?
可愛い、これ可愛いな。みんな嬉しいな。
Cute, this is cute. Everyone's happy.
はい、ということでね、これもちりとしたあの、にゃこぴーのぬいぐるみなので、みんな買って下さい！
So, since this is a fluffy Neko-pi plushie, everyone please buy it!
はい、みこが一番嬉しい。
Yeah, Miko's the happiest.
そして、なんと！ なんとなんとなんとなんと！ ドドン！
And what's more! What, what, what, what! Ta-da!
なんと！ フルセットご購入特典では、（はぁ...はぁ...）このポストカードに、え、直筆サイン入りポストカード、え、みんなに！みんなに！みんなに！みんなに届けて、マジ！うわぁー！
And! As a full set purchase bonus... (Gasp...) This postcard comes with a handwritten signed postcard, delivered to everyone, everyone, everyone, everyone! Seriously, waaah!
はい、ということでね、まあ、今回は争いが起きません。とても平和な直筆サイン！ということで、みこはまた感銘されますけど、みんなにね、まあ感謝の気持ちを込めて、え、書きたいと思いますので、
Right, so, well, there'll be no fights this time. A very peaceful handwritten signature! So, Miko is touched once again, and with feelings of gratitude toward everyone, I want to write them...
みんな買ってね！買ってね！直筆欲しいか？欲しいよな！はい、ということで、
Everyone buy it! Buy it! Do you want a handwritten one? You want it, right! So,
それでは最後の2曲を気持ちを込めて歌って、踊るので、みんな見ててね！
Now, I'll sing and dance the last two songs with all my heart, so everyone watch!
好きになって　もっと私を見て　もっと
Fall in love with me, look at me more, more!
私をみてもっと　アンサーは
Look at me more, the answer is
愛のこもった投げキッスで
a loving kiss thrown to you!
気のせいじゃない　目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って　愛しちゃってください
Make a heart and please fall in love with me!
やれること　なんでもします
I'll do anything I can do,
遠慮なしで　手当たり次第挑戦
trying everything without holding back.
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti comments found through ego-searching—
嘘御伽草子よりわかってるし
I understand that better than fake fairy tales,
でも大丈夫　ここに叫ば　みんながいる
but it's alright, when I shout here, everyone is here!
好きになって　もっと私を見て　もっと
Fall in love with me, look at me more, more!
愛のこもった投げキッスで
with a loving kiss thrown to you!
虜にする！　もっと夢を見せる！　もっと
I'll captivate you! Show you more dreams! More!
楽しんでって　愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourselves on this loving special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も　書いてください
Please write letters to me too,
何度も読んで　宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure!
好きゃんだふる　まだ早いけど
"Suki-wonderful," it's still early, but
裏切りません　宣言しときます
I declare I won't betray you!
失敗ばかりじゃ負けない　うさぎんだ実績で勝ってやる
I won't lose just to failures, I'll win with my achievements!
だからやれない　負けず嫌い　私はいる
That's why I won't give up, I'm a sore loser, and I'm here!
好きになって！　もっと汗をかいて！　もっと
Fall in love with me! Sweat more! More!
愛のこもったmikoビームで
with a loving Miko beam!
大歓声！　もっとまだまだねえ？　もっと
Great cheers! More, still not enough? More!
受け止めてね　愛のこもったわがままソング
Accept it, please, my loving selfish song!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
はぁ…終わりが近づく　寂しいね
Ah... the end is approaching, how lonely.
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も次も　また会えるよね？
We'll meet again next time, right?
約束！
Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も　心ない誰かの言葉さえも
Words overflowing with kindness, and even the heartless words of someone,
必要なんだ　必要なんだ　強くなるため
they're necessary, they're necessary, to become stronger!
好きにさじょで！　もっと楽しんじゃえ！　もっと
Fall in love! Enjoy yourselves more! More!
忘れないで　特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, may this be a special day!
共に歌おう ずっと！共に歩もう ずっと！
Together let's sing forever! Together let's walk forever!
愛言葉はとびっきりのL・O・V・E
Love words are a surprising L-O-V-E
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Love you more! See me more! More!
恩返しは“愛のこめた投げキスで”（Fooo!!）
Our reward is "with a loving thrown kiss" (Fooo!)
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love more! See me more! More!
恩返しは“愛のこめた投げキスで”（Fooo!!）
Our reward is "with a loving thrown kiss" (Fooo!)
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
Make them captive! More! Show them dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこめたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy a special night filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω＜)
I'm gonna give you fan service! (・ω＜)
箱にあたる陽を横目で眺めて
Gazing sideways at the sun hitting the box,
そっと陰る木の根に一人で比べてた
I compared myself alone at the root of a softly casting tree.
積もる溜息を吹き払うように
As if to blow away the piling sighs,
そんな私を君が見つけてくれたんだ
You found someone like me.
そう それは恋のような
Yes, it's like love.
ぬくもりを全部 君に笑顔咲かせたら
If I make you smile with all this warmth,
桜風に踊る空 君と出会ったこの場所で
In the sky dancing with cherry blossom winds, at this place where I met you,
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっと 溢れそうになるかな
I wonder if so many memories are about to overflow.
君と流した涙は 明日の笑顔の糧にしよう
Let's make the tears we shed together the nourishment for tomorrow's smiles.
膝をついていたって ほら 何度だっていいよ
Even if you're on your knees, hey, however many times is fine.
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Putting on airs, feeling ashamed, teasing—even so,
君が傍でで見守ってくれてたこと わかってるから
I know that you've been watching over me close by.
追い風を受けて とまらない日々も そっとくじけそうになって
Even days of endless tailwinds becoming faint and breaking,
心が渦巻いた 積もる溜息で また泣きかけても
With my heart churning and piling sighs making me want to cry again,
あたたかな手で ずっと支えてくれたんだ
You've always supported me with your warm hands.
ほら 耳をすませば
Hey, if you listen closely,
一人じゃないから
You're not alone.
諦めかけて 心が閉じても
Even if you give up and your heart closes,
君が背中を押してくれたよね
You pushed my back, didn't you?
春の蕾が花開く頃は
When spring buds are about to blossom,
隣で笑い合おうね
Let's laugh together side by side.
桜風に踊る空 君と出会ったこの場所で
In the sky dancing with cherry blossom winds, at this place where I met you,
どれくらいの思い出ぎゅっと 溢れそうになるかな
I wonder if so many memories are about to overflow.
君と描くこの花は 未来もきっと残るから
The flowers we draw together will surely remain in the future.
汗をかいた分は そうさ 強くなれるんだ
The sweat we shed will make us stronger, that's right.
意地を張って 恥をかいて いじけたって それでも
Putting on airs, feeling ashamed, teasing—even so,
君が傍で見守ってくれたから ありがとうだよ
I know that you've been watching over me close by, thank you so much.
みんな お誕生日を祝ってくれて 本当にありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for celebrating my birthday!
君と出会えたこの空 これからもっと咲かせるよ
In this sky where I met you, I'll make them bloom even more from now on!
この後すぐ メンバー限定
Members-only stream right after this!